Okay, so in the last video we showed you
how you could make a comparison and how
it would return either true or false
depending on the result of that
comparison. In this video I'm going to
show you how you can control what your
code does based on that um based on the
returned value. So the way you do that
when you want to make a decision you use
the keyword if. So you'll say if
password
is exactly the same as the entered
password and then you put curly braces
hit enter and now whatever you type
between this code these lines of code
will only happen if the passwords match.
So we could say alert
the
welcome to the system.
So, it's going to compare password to
password and then all of this entire
expression is going to reduce down to
either true or false. So, they either
entered the right password or they did
not. If it comes out as true, then we're
going to tell them welcome to the
system. If it doesn't, then we're not
going to do anything. Um, so we're going
to say if the passwords are the same,
alert, welcome to the system. So, let's
see this in action. So, we'll hit go
live.
And it says, "What is your password?"
So, if I type a bunch of gibberish and
hit enter, it says false. And then
nothing else shows. Um, so if we come
back over to our code, that's what we
expected because we entered the
password. Um, and then it alerted false.
And then because this is false, it
skipped over line 24 and went to the
end. Let's try that again, but this time
we'll enter the right password. So,
we'll reload the page and it says, "What
is your password?" We'll say password.
Hit okay. And it says true. Welcome to
the system. So, this time the alert
message did show up because we
successfully met the condition we used.
So you can use an if statement to
control the flow of your